A Guide to the James Rogers McConnell Memorial Collections
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Correspondence
  - Letters from James Rogers McConnell to Paul Ayres Rockwell
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 May 14; 8 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [writes of a Mr. Terry [Thierry-Delanone ?], citing him as a charming man and possibly having been in diplomatic work; living at the advance point due to heavy work load and the French section being ordered away to another point; expects six new cars and drivers; electricity wiped out by an obus clipping the wires; describes scene at the postes de secour where soldiers have come down to rest; comments on the French soldier]
    - James R. McConnell, Pont-à-Mousson, to Paul A. Rockwell, Hospital No. 101, Rumes (in care of Kiffin Yates Rockwell), 1915 May 18; 12 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [sympathy for Kiffin's severe injuries in the terrible fight; horrifying news that nearly the entire regiment is gone; comments on Thierry-Delanone slipping them inside news; describes in detail being under attack and the activities of the ambulances; now driving the contagious car]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Hospital No. 101, Rumes, Ille et Vilaine (in care of Kiffin Yates Rockwell), [1915] May 18; APCS (Box Box 2)
      [sent letter by Thierry-Delanone upon hearing of Kiffin's wounds; offers assistance]
    - James R. McConnell, [Pont-à-Mousson] to Paul A. Rockwell, Hospital No. 101, Rumes, Ille et Vilaine (in care of Kiffin Rockwell), 1915 May 25; 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [news of Italy's involvement; describes the dreadful scene when he went to the first-line trenches to see the burying of the dead French and German soldiers behind the lines; Zora Lee Fry visiting her uncle; crops look good; Paris sending big Hotchkiss care for sitting cases]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, 1915 May 27; 6 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 2)
      [wishes for Kiffin's recovery; Thierry-Delanone wounded in yesterday's bombardment; twenty people, mostly women and children, were killed and thirty-five wounded; description of mangled bodies and destruction in the village; loss of civilians shocking; saw three hundred Greek volunteers]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, [1915 ca. May]; APCS (Box Box 2)
      [postcard of "bombardement de Pont-à-Mousson"]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Hospital No. 101 (Salle Pasteur), Rumes, Ille et Vilaine (in care of Kiffin Yates Rockwell), 1915 Jun 3; APCS (Box Box 2)
      [inquires of his whereabouts and Kiffin's recovery]
    - James R. McConnell, Neuilly-sur-Seine, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Jun 10; 9 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [refugees leaving for Paris; bombardments so bad that the hospitals are closed and they have to evacuate all the way to Dieulouard; description of a shell attack on the hospital; voyage to the Gros Chêne where they bury the dead; [Ned] Salisbury]
    - James R. McConnell, Neuilly-sur-Seine, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Jun 24; 8 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [inquires of Jeanne [Paul's fiancé ?], Marcelle Guérin, and the Vicomte du Peloux; less wounded; to be given the work of the adjacent division also; will go beyond the last point of call of Auberge St. Pierre to Feyen Haye, Limey, and Flirey; Captain Watts, the Australian aviator in the French service, and Lieutenant Noel, the famous military flier, lunched with them; inquires of [William] Thaw; relates Watts' views on the English; wrote article on the American section and wants to write more for publication; mentions Sydney Adamson and Arthur Page in connection with writing; relates tale of Watts and Noel going out to the trenches; while on duty at Dieulouard had a concert with men from an Algerian battery; comments on the involvement of the several countries in the war, including Italy, Austria, France, Russia and England]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Jun 26; 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 2)
      [inquires of Paul, his fiancé, and brother [Kiffin Yates Rockwell]; quiet, no bombardments]
    - James R. McConnell, Neuilly-sur-Seine, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Jun 27; 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [inquires of the Vicomte du Peloux; comments on Kiffin's improvement; declares strong friendship toward Paul; Germans bombarding first line trenches]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, [1915 Jun]; APCS (Box Box 2)
      [much work now]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Jul 1; 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 2)
      [comments on reports on the war in newspapers; six new cars, detached from the tent section, to be sent to take up back work; family refusing to send more money]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Jul 3; 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 2)
      [plans for an American Fourth of July celebration; Germans shelled cluster of houses where some of the postes de secours are located; terrific bombardment of trenches]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Jul 8; 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [Captain Watts and Lieutenant Noel, the aviators, were guests at the Fourth of July celebration; wounds frightful; Germans using gas and then throwing petrol jets on the choking soldiers; R. J. Cunningham, African lion hunter, has joined the section; describes the changes that have occurred in the outfit; inquires of Elizabeth "Betty" Baldwin]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Jul 16; 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [Leif Norman] Barclay; discussion of publicity given McConnell; his sketch of the life of his section; Ambassador [Robert] Bacon (1860-1919) and wife [Martha Waldron Cowdin]; [Abram Piatt] Andrew (1873-1936); fighting in the Quart en Reserve; Russian retreats on side of Allies; treated soldiers wounded by grenades]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Jul 22; 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [inquires of marriage plans; activities of the telephonists at the trench switchboards and the artillerymen; [Charles Chocteau] Johnson and [Lawrence] Rumsey near Dunkirk; Ned Salisbury in Paris]
    - James R. McConnell, Calvados, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Jul 29; 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [news of Waldo Pierce; high explosive 'marmites' came through town causing casualties; death of Frenchman Maignot; Medicine Divisionale has removed the last Ambulance from Pont-à-Mousson so they have to evacuate to Dieulouard at night; Lieutenant Kullman left for Dieulouard; German attack previous night a failure]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Aug 3; 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [bureau moved to a sporty estate; describes shelling of area; Elizabeth "Betty" Baldwin sailing for the states; William Thaw seen in Toul]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Aug 15; APCS (Box Box 2)
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1915 Aug 25; 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 2)
      [comments on Woodrow Wilson needing to do something about the Arabic incident; wonderful weather, quiet]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, 1915 Sep 10; APCS (Box Box 2)
      [orders to leave for a new post]
    - James R. McConnell, Haute Saone, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 May 9; 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [thanks for the candy; machines have arrived; has own aeroplane and crew; first flightin "Baby"; [Elliot Christopher] Cowdin still on permission; [Norman] Price went to get his machine at Le Bourget; no word from Mowrer]
    - James R. McConnell, Escadrille N. 124, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, [1916] May 20; 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [news of Kiffin Yates Rockwell bringing down a German; Germans dropped bombs, killing five and wounding more; orders to leave Luxeuil for Bar-le-Duc; Norman Price; [Elliot Christopher] Cowdin; money for Gros from the committee; possible reward and medals for Kiffin]
    - James R. McConnell, Luxeuil, to Paul A.] Rockwell, Paris, [1916 ca. May 22]; APCS (Box Box 2)
      [waiting at Luxeuil; [Bert] Hall sunk a German near Verdun; nothing to write about even for Mowrer]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 May 28; 6 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [two little boards came and were for an 18 meter so had a makeshift made in Belfort; plans for a mission over the Bois-le-Prêtre; news of Kiffin Yates Rockwell's and [William] Thaw's wounds; looking forward to Verdun; [Norman] Price and [Bert] Hall smashed; Grundy writes that the
      Sun
      wants McConnell as aviation correspondent; asks Paul to make terms with Grundy and keep it a secret; hopes for twenty percent of moving picture returns; inquires if [Elizabeth] "Betty" [Baldwin] is back in Paris]
    - James R. McConnell, Bar de Meuse, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Jun 3; 4 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [heard from Grundy; left Luxeuil and spent night in Toul; landed in present place and asked to go on mission; "Lovebury" [Gervais Raoul Victor Lufbery], [Bert] Hall, Captain T[henault], [Elliot Christopher] Cowdin, [Norman] Prince, and [Victor] Chapman all on mission to fight the fourteen "Boches" [Germans]; Germans used explosive bullets; his old American Ambulance section working on ground; [Walter] Lovell directed cars; forty killed and two-hundred wounded in town; description of his first fight with a German; some damage to his machine; headed south west and eventually hit the field at St. Dizier where everyone smashes]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, [1916] Jun 8; 4 p. (electrostatic copy) (Box Box 2)
      [rain and clouds and nothing going on; Bar-le-Duc is closed to them; [Lawrence] Rumsey has arrived; [Norman] Prince was out; seems to be a split up in this outfit [William] Thaw and company vs. [Elliot Christopher] Cowdin, [Norman] Prince, et al.; received letter from Elizabeth "Betty" Baldwin in her own hand; has new machine; memorial service; [Walter] Lovell, [Leif Norman] Barclay and Willis [Haviland] leaving to join aviation; heard from Marcelle Guérin]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Jun 15; 2 p. (electrostatic copy) (Box Box 2)
      [comments on how he has the outfit sized up; comments on Kiffin Yates Rockwell, [William] Thaw, [Victor] Chapman, [Gervais Raoul Victor] Lufbery as being serious and on [Norman] Prince and [Elliot Christopher] Cowdin being in it for the sport; further comments on [Bert] Hall, [Charles Chocteau] Johnson, [Lawrence] Rumsey, [Horace Clyde] Balsley, and [Dudley Lawrence] Hill; trying to get "Skipper" there; American pilots not as good as French pilots; wrote to Paulette, one of the mannequin friends]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, [1916] Jun 21; 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [[Horace Clyde] Balsley's wound caused by an explosive bullet while caught between four "Boches" [Germans]; [Victor] Chapman broke McConnell's machine; [Charles Chocteau] Johnson lost; mentions "my sweet smelling friend of Kodak"; [Didier] Masson with them now; [Elliot Christopher] Cowdin trying to get leave because of his nerves]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Jun 25; 1 p. (Box Box 2)
      [death of Victor [Chapman] who was the bravest of all; wishes it had been someone like [Elliot Christopher] Cowdin; Gros was out today]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Jun 26; 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [remembers Sudbury and socks he sent to Paul; Kiffin Yates Rockwell, [Horace Clyde] Balsley, [Charles Chocteau] Johnson, Victor [Chapman] and McConnell passed sergeant today; loss of [William] Thaw, [Horace Clyde] Balsley, and [Victor] Chapman may make prospective volunteers rethink decision; expect "Skipper" soon; [Willis] Havi[land]; Norman Prince not bad; inquires of Lieutenant Noel]
    - James R. McConnell, Escadrille N. 124, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, [1916] Jul 1; 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [surprised at developments concerning [Bert] Hall; [Carroll Dana] Winslow trying some sort of line as Sayles; Norman [Prince] predicted that Hall would follow in the footsteps of [Elliot Christopher] Cowdin; calls Cowdin an awful liar; Captain is off on permission; Lieutenant [de Laage de Meux] running the squadron; discusses action dives on avatiks and Fokkers; Kiffin Yates Rockwell thinks the lieutenant is too wild; have learned certain precautions to follow during aerial warfare; "Skipper" has not returned; Grundy; remembers Victor [Chapman]]
    - James R. McConnell, Escadrille N. 124, to Paul A. Rockwell, 1916 Jul 16; 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [calls attention to large
      Review
      issue; letter from "Skipper" that says [Frederick William] Zinn could not fly well enough so was made a mitrailleur (gunner); inquires about a dog that Madame Jochin wants to get rid of; Marcelle [Guérin] rest cure in Evian les Bains going well; big time on Bastille Day; [Lawrence] Rumsey and [Charles Chocteau] Johnson could not fly for awhile afterward; wants to write short article for the
    - James R. McConnell, Escadrille N. 124, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Jul 19; 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [heard from Grundy who had asked "Skipper" for information on how pilots are trained; sent good line of mail stuff to Mowrer which does not conflict with the
      [Bert] Hall back now with a yarn about chasing a spy; [Norman] Prince saved him]
    - James R. McConnell, Escadrille N. 124, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, [1916] Jul 25; 8 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [received photographs; expects "Skipper" any day; [Walter Hines] Page, editor of
      World's Work
      , wants an article on American aviators that Eyre will write and have run under McConnell's name; deal with Grundy has been lucrative; boys in the trenches are bearing the brunt of the war and not getting what they deserve; [Bert] Hall killed another German; [Lawrence] Rumsey and [Dudley Lawrence] Hill made sergeants and [Norman] Prince adjutant; [Horace Clyde] Balsley to go to Paris; reasons only four machines are currently in commission, including how [Norman] Prince's and [Gervais Raoul Victor] Lufbery's machines became disabled; Lieutenant Chafrot wounded; has written on thoughts of American aviators going back]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, [1916] Aug 25; 3 p. (electrostatic copy) (Box Box 2)
      [being evacuated to the hospital at Bar-le-Duc for two or three weeks; says its a shame because his new machine is ready; [Charles Chocteau] Johnson pulled off an attack; news of Norman [Prince] and [Elliot Christopher] Cowdin; enclose letter to sister for Pechkoff; heard from [Walter Hines] Page about article and Eyre; advises Kiffin Yates Rockwell to play it safe]
    - James R. McConnell, Escadrille N. 124, Vitry le François, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, [1916] Aug 26; APCS (Box Box 2)
      [laid up in a depot d' eclopés]
    - James R. McConnell, Escadrille N. 124, Vitry le François, to Paul A. Rockwell, 1916 Aug 31; 2 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 2)
      [sorry that Paul's eyes are bothering him; received two interesting books from Marcelle [Guérin]; discusses illness of a personal nature and also back pain; conditions in a sort of ward and in the infirmary; thinks that Eyre is getting a good sum of money on his work]
    - James R. McConnell, Vitry le François, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Sep 4; 4 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [heard from Grundy; hope [Lawrence] Rumsey has sense to keep him; back has not improved any marked degree; escadrille is leaving Bar-le-Duc; will probably see him when he rejoins the escadrille; asks Paul not to mention it to their young lady friends; two pilots instructing at Newport News, Virginia training school claim to have served in France; mother wishes to get him a release and has sent him a check; comments on Marcelle [Guérin] and her Russian beau; concert on Sunday included "ditty about picking up a queen on his permission and getting a frightful and torturing dose"; comments on reactions of the men, saying that many of the gentlemen may have had "unwise love affairs"; greetings to Kiffin Yates Rockwell]
    - James R. McConnell, Hôpital Mixte, Vitry le François, Marne, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Sep 7; APCS (Box Box 2)
      [unhappy with move to this hospital; back is the same, receives no treatment; will have to report to his depot at Dijon]
    - James R. McConnell to Paul A. Rockwell, [1916 Sep 9]; APCS (Box Box 2)
      [sends postcard of "L' Hôpital Général, Vitry-le-François"; claims to be much better]
    - James R. McConnell, Hôpital Mixte, Vitry le François, to Paul A. Rockwell, 1916 Sep 9; 2 p. on 1 l. w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [discouraged over progress of back, other problem almost all right; wants to get back since he can at least sit in an aeroplane; wants only a few days to get into condition; plans to visit for a few days; uniform has not arrived yet; asks Paul to cash the check from his mother; comments on lack of protest from America over Lille outrage]
    - James R. McConnell, Hôpital Mixte, Vitry le François, Marne, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Sep 12; 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [good news about Kiffin Yates Rockwell and the snowbird; trying a new elixir tomorrow; 2,000 motor lorries came through in route for Somme to move troops to the Champagne offensive; may be ten days before he is released from hospital; uniform must be lost; inquires about letter for Pechkoff; mentions Grundy and Munsey; encloses theatre program, "Programme for Théâtre du Parc/Dépot des Eclopés de Vitry-le-François/Concert/Du Dimanche 3 Septembre 1916"]
    - James R. McConnell, Hôpital Mixte, Vitry le François, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Sep 16; 2 p.on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [his back is better and he hopes to get out soon; Elizabeth "Betty" Baldwin has been sending magazines and letters; forty in the ward now so no more massages; poor conditions in hospital; war seems to be moving towards the end; [E. A.] Marshall got another citation at Verdun; De Sillac transferred to aviation]
    - James R. McConnell, Hôpital Mixte, Vitry le François, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Sep 19; APCS (Box Box 2)
      [thanks for the information on his escadrille going to Luxeuil; no news from Eyre; in bed again]
    - James R. McConnell, [Hôpital Mixte, Vitry le François], to Paul A. Rockwell, 1916 Sep 21; 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 2)
      [sending first sheets of "eclopé speil"; E. A. Marshall hails from Long Island, New York; discusses Marshall's accomplishments in the war; De Sillac slated for aviation and is also a good writer; Eyre says no news from [Walter Hines] Page; discouraged over the condition of his back; poor conditions at hospital; wrote Polly Root and her committee for supplies and assistance; inquires about [Willis] Haviland; beginning the "eclopé speil"; comments on Yvonne and wonders if she will catch on; freezing without his clothes which are with the escadrille; heard from "Skipper" about Luxeuil]
    - "Chout" [Charles Chocteau Johnson], Luxeuil-les-Bains, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Oct 2; 1 p. w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [everything about the same; enclosing discourse of the Captain; invites him to work and club around with them in Luxeuil]
    - James R. McConnell, [Escadrille N. 124], to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, [1916] Nov 15; 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 2)
      [misty and rainy climate; no machine yet; thanks for sending
      Captain T[hénault] at Cazean; have Bill's [William Thaw] bunk in the shed witih "Havi" [Willis Haviland]; many old friends have gone since he was last at the front; Germans dropping bombs on clear nights; "Skip" to try night flying in Nieuport]
    - James R. McConnell, [Escadrille N. 124], to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, [1916] Nov 19; 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [told the boys about Paul's wedding; German attack destroyed sixteen planes, wounded nine and killed one; "Skip" tried his first night flight; Bert Hall is at their field; "Luff" [Gervais Raoul Victor Lufbery] went to Paris; cold weather bothers his back; [Dudley Lawrence] Hill will write soon; dined with some British officers; has "Luff's" old machine; cannot do work for [Walter Hines] Page due to the cold; have not heard from Hélène or Marcelle [Guérin]]
    - James R. McConnell, [Escadrille N. 124], to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, [ca. 1916 Nov 21]; 1 p. w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [inquires about the "civil ceremony"; "Skip" has returned; trying to work on the article]
    - James R. McConnell, [Escadrille N. 124], to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Dec 11; 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [honored to be asked to witness Paul's wedding; not feeling well and "Whiskey" chewed his fingers so it is hard to hold a pen to write the article; will send the rest of it by Dudley [Lawrence Hill]; has only flown once since his return; hats off to [Herman Lincoln] Chatkoff; expects [Ronald Wood] Hoskier and [Edmond Charles Clinton] Genêt soon; [E. A.] Marshall was made a mechanic because of his heart; squadron moving next month; no news to send Grundy; regards to his wife]
    - James R. McConnell, [Escadrille N. 124], to Mrs. Weeks, Paris, on verso ANS to Paul A. Rockwell, [1916] Dec 15; 3 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [concerning her stay in Paris; says that the stove is the greatest success; [Ronald Wood] Hoskier has arrived; may go to Dax after the others arrive; [Dudley Lawrence] Hill sends best; "Skip" will write soon]
    - James R. McConnell, [Escadrille N. 124], to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Dec 17; 4 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 2)
      [delighted to have received the gem of a cigarette case as a keepsake from him; heard from "Skipper" the details of Paul's present life; bad weather has prevented flying; many pilots have fallen ill, including Lieutenant de Laage [de Meux]; working on the article; [Ronald Wood] Hoskier has arrived; regards to Paul's wife]
      [Notes by William James Kenneth Rockwell concerning Rockwell's marriage and the cigarette case]
    - James R. McConnell, Escadrille N. 124, to Paul A. Rockwell, Paris, 1916 Dec 21; APCS (Box Box 2)
      [concerning the pages of the article]
    - Edwin A. Alderman, President of the University of Virginia, to Sarah Rogers McConnell, Seabreeze, Florida, 1917 Mar 28 (Box Box 2)
      [expresses the University of Virginia's sorrow over the death of her son, James Rogers McConnell; expresses the desire of the University to place a memorial there to McConnell]
    - Sarah Rogers McConnell, Seabreeze, Florida, to Paul Ayres Rockwell, Paris, France, 1917 Apr 4; 7 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 2)
      [moving letter about the death of her son, James Rogers McConnell; feels that he is nearer in spirit than when fighting so far away; is inspired and uplifted by his love for France and fight for human rights; believes that he was engaged to be married to Mlle. Hélène Dé Bouchet; Edwin Anderson Alderman's tribute to her son and his intentions to ask permission of the French government to bring her son's remains to be buried in the grounds of the University of Virginia; requests help with his belongings because of Rockwell's loyal and devoted friendship with McConnell; wishes to have her son's name in full, including his middle name and her maiden name, Rogers; comments that her son and his brother, Kiffin Yates Rockwell, are united in eternal fellowship]
      [Notes by William James Kenneth Rockwell concerning this letter]
- Printed and Miscellaneous
  - Art work signed "L.B." with comment on inside "Made at front," used as stationery by James Rogers McConnell. Removed from John Lloyd Newcomb's copy of Flying for France [D603.M2 1917 Copy 1], [ca. 1916-1917] (Box Box 2)